Donovan Theseira

Full-Stack Software Developer

Phone 858-699-4251

E-mail dt@donovant.me Website www.donovant.me

A consummate, progressing software engineer with 3+ years of experience, who views every new project like a puzzle with unlimited pieces and infinite ways to finding the solution. At SSAI, led the development of a number of new features to give users more access to data and new ways to connect.

Skills

Client Side

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, ES6

Server Side

Java, bash, JSP, C#, Razor

Frameworks

Liferay (6.2 & 7), jQuery, Angular.js, ASP.NET, Bootstrap, EF6, Google Maps

Database Servers

PostgreSQL, MSSQL, MySQL

Gaining Experience

Docker, Jenkins, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Python, React

iQuery Plugins

¡Query UI, DataTables

Experience

June 2016 - Present

Software Developer II

Science Systems and Applications, Inc (SSAI)

- Led the upgrade development on the Liferay portal and ported a majority of the custom overrides to the system in Java.
- Worked on implementing unit testing and to help redesign the development life cycle currently being used with JUnit.
- Led the development of a project in Java which gives the users a way to create and join teams, view data, and "compete" with other users across the world.
- Added new features, using Java and Angular 1, to the NASA GLOBE Observer App that allows users to create, find, and join a team.
- Decreased page load times by as much as 30 seconds using asynchronous techniques with both Java and PostgreSQL database functions.
- Key developer in 40% of a major redesign of www.globe.gov, including creating new PostgreSQL functions and making the site more responsive.
- Developed 10% of a major project for NASA, which displayed changing air temperatures during the Eclipse in 2017.

May 2016 - Present

Programming Consultant

Veneklasen Associates

- Implemented a project management web-application using C# and the Entity Framework.
- Created a MSSQL database, hosted on Azure, with continuous integration.

Education

September 2011 – June 2016 California State Polytechnic University, Pomona

Bachelor of Science, Computer Information Systems

Projects

SmartMirror App Display data pulled from Google Maps, Geocoding, and Geolocation, Spotify, Dark Sky, CryptoCompare, and IEX API's. The data is displayed in sections, showing general information about what we look at quite often as well as show a motivational quote to keep you going through the day.

Goodnight Messenger Google Chrome Extension that gives Facebook Messenger a dark theme.